Michael Döringer



Music and data analytics professional; recently obtained the Google Advanced Data Analytics Certificate. Proficient in all relevant tools and platforms for data analysis. Highly motivated with exceptional attention to detail stemming from 10+ years of experience in the music industry as an editor and journalist

Languages =

German (native), English (fluent)

Address 🏫

Innstr. 30, 12043 Berlin

Phone 📞

+49 160 94872921

Mail 📦

doeringer.michael@gmail.com

Portfolio III ~/

https://hugolargo.github.io/

Education

05/2023

Google Advanced Data Analytics Certificate

01/2023-03/2023

Data Analytics Boot Camp

Spiced Academy Berlin

2011-2014

Cultural Journalism (MA)

Universität der Künste Berlin (UdK)

2008-2011

Popular Music and Media Studies (BA)

Universität Paderborn

Skills & Tools

- Python
- R
- SQL
- Data Cleaning, EDA, Statistics
- Tableau
- Excel | Google Sheets
- all other Office apps

Professional experience

2020-2022

Music Data Editor & Team Lead Musicology

Moodagent Deutschland

- successfully prepared database and music metadata for the launch of the music streaming service in Germany
- improved the Al supported music recommendation system with data-driven QAing
- designed and managed weekly release plans in Google Spreadsheets
- collaborated with Data Scientists and global music teams in DK, IN, AUS/NZ
- successfully lead a team of 4

2017-2020

Cultural Validator for Apple Marcom

via Hogarth Worldwide

 selected, analyzed and approved of content for Apple marketing purposes in GSA on weekly basis

2015-2020

Lead Copywriter for Apple Music DE

via Hogarth Worldwide + Bridgehead Media

- contributed 5000+ pieces of original writing, editing, localization and translation
- shaped the editorial voice of Apple Music since its launch in 2015
- participated in workshops with Apple in London

2014-2020

Freelance Editor and Writer

for magazines, online media and record labels

- Universal Music: boosted digital catalogue curation, helped Marketing team with editorial consulting and playlist creation
- regularly contributed to publications like Spex, Groove, Das Filter, Mixmag, Electronic Beats, Vice

2011-2013

Staff Editor

De:Bug Magazine

- planned monthly print magazine issues
- supervised review section
- mentored freelance writers and interns
- · editing, proof-reading and layout adjustments